Zankoku na tenshi no you ni
Just like the cruel angel
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
2D4U PRESENTS:
Aoi kaze ga ima
Even though the untested breeze...
mune no doa o tataitemo
...taps at the door to your heart
Watashi dake o tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata
You just look solely at me and smile
Sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuu de
So intent on seeking out that gentle touch
Unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi
Such innocent eyes, still ignorant of their destiny
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
But someday, you are sure to realize...
sono senaka ni wa
...that upon your back
Haruka mirai mezasu tame
You have the wings with which to fly...
no hane ga aru koto
...towards the distant future
Zankoku na tenshi no teeze
The cruel angel's thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobidatsu
Soon, you will take flight from the windowsill
Hotobashiru atsui patosu de
With your torrent of ardent pathos
Omoide o uragiru nara
If you are to betray our memories
Kono sora o daite kagayaku
You, who embrace these heavens and shine
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
Are you ready, Shinji?
Yes.
Release the final safety lock!
Evangelion Unit 01, lift off!
Shinji, just concentrate on walking right now.
Walk...
It walked!
Shinji, get it together!
Hurry! Get up!
Shinji, calm down! That's not your arm!
What's going on with the
Eva's defense system?
The signal's not working!
The field's not deploying!
Have we failed?
Left arm damaged!
The circuits have disconnected!
Shinji, dodge!
There's a crack on the front of the cranium!
The armor won't last much longer!
The head's been damaged!
Extent of damage, unknown!
The control nerves are disconnecting
one after another!
We're not getting any readings on the pilot!
Shinji!
I don't know this ceiling.
EPISODE 02
UNFAMILIAR
CEILING
So, the Angels have returned, eh?
It's so sudden.
It's the same as it was fifteen years ago.
A disaster comes as it will, without warning.
We could say it was fortunate, in the sense
that our prior investments were not a waste.
You can't be sure about that yet.
If it doesn't pay off, it's a waste all the same.
Precisely. Now that the Angels,
and the fact that we have been
manipulating information,
have become public knowledge,
Nerv must operate in a speedy
and prudent manner.
It's already been taken care of.
You may rest assured of that.
In regards to the declaration of
the special state of emergency,
government officials have announced...
This incident was...
UN forces in Japan...
So it's public scenario B-22.
In response to reporters' questions...
No, there's no threat of contamination
from the center of the explosion.
So, we're hushing up the truth again?
But at least our PR people are thrilled
The only Angel samples collected
were adhered to the Eva.
Now that they've finally got something to do.
We're being pretty casual about it.
Correct, as in the model simulation,
approximately 99.9% of it evaporated.
I don't know about that.
I think everyone's actually scared.
Of course we are.
Well, we must acknowledge that.
Speaking of which, Ikari,
isn't there a better way to
utilize Nerv and Eva?
First the repairs to Unit 00,
and now to Unit 01, which you
wrecked in its first battle.
It's enough to bankrupt an entire country.
We also understand that you
gave that toy to your son.
Manpower, time, and money.
How much more do you and your family
plan on wasting?
And that is not your only responsibility.
Top Secret
Human Instrumentality Project
United Nations Top Executive Meeting
17th Midterm Report
Human Instrumentality Committee
2015 Business Plan Outline Summary
The Human Instrumentality Project,
that should be your top priority.
Precisely.
Under these desperate circumstances,
that project is our one and only hope.
In any case, we cannot excuse any delays
in that project's schedule
due to the reappearance of the Angels.
We will consider the issue
regarding the budget.
Now, the rest of this meeting
concerns only the committee.
Your presence here was appreciated, Ikari.
Ikari, there is no turning back.
I know.
Mankind has no time left.
Air conditioning has just got to be
mankind's greatest treasure.
It's the triumph of science over nature.
Shinji's woken up.
How is he?
No external injuries. His memory
is a bit muddled, however.
You don't think it could it be
mental contamination?
There appears to be no cause for worry.
Really?
I suppose he did have a pretty hectic day.
It's not suprising. His cranial nerves
took a lot of strain.
Don't you mean his heart?
Construction Plan Notice
Okay, okay. Keep it coming. Good!
If Eva and this city both operate
at their full potential,
maybe we can make it through this.
Are you going to defeat the Angels?
You're always such an optimist.
Hey, sometimes you need a little wishful
thinking just to keep on living.
I see your point. It helps to
hear things like that from you.
See ya!
Are you sure?
They don't want to live together?
I think that living apart is natural
for Ikari and his son.
And being together is unnatural?
Shinji Ikari
Alone?
Right. His room will be in the 6th Block,
just beyond this one.
Is that satisfactory?
Yes.
Are you sure?
Shinji...
It's fine. I'd rather be alone.
Anywhere is fine.
What?!
So, I said, I'll take care of Shinji.
I've already got permission from the brass.
Hey, it's not like I'm going to
"put the moves" on a kid.
Of course you're not!
What the hell are you thinking?
You're always like that. Honestly!
She just can't take a joke.
Well, we'll have to have a party tonight, right?
What for?
A welcoming party for my
new roommate, of course!
So, you're going to move after all?
Yes. I never dreamed that this city
would become a battlefield.
Yeah.
My husband's saying that our kid and I
should evacuate, at the very least.
Evacuate, huh?
This city may be a fortress, but that's
no guarantee of safety.
Just remembering yesterday
gives me the chills.
I hope you don't mind if we make
a little stop on the way.
Where?
Someplace really cool.
It's just such a lonely city.
It's time.
Amazing! The buildings are growing!
This city is a fortress, designed to
protect against the Angels.
This is New Tokyo-3.
This is our city.
And it's the city that you helped to protect.
Your things should have already
been delivered, Shinji.
The truth is, I just recently moved
to this city too.
Come on in.
Pardon the intrusion.
Shinji, this is YOUR home now.
I'm home.
Welcome home.
As you can see, the place
is a little bit messy,
but make yourself comfortable.
You call this
a "little bit" messy?
Oh! Sorry! Could you put the food
in the fridge?
Sure.
Ice,
snacks,
and nothing but beer.
What kind of a life does she lead?
Excuse me. What's in the other fridge?
Oh, don't mind that.
He's probably still sleeping!
Sleeping?
Let's eat!
Let's eat.
Life just doesn't get any better than this!
Don't you want to eat?
It's pretty good, even if it is instant.
I'm sorry, I'm just not used to it.
That's no excuse! You can't be so finicky.
No, that's not what I... well...
Isn't this nice?
Having dinner with somebody else!
Uh, yes.
Here we go for the next one.
Rock, paper, scissors...
Pon! Pon! Pon! Pon!
Sorry, Shinji.
Our Chores Chart
Day/Chore     Su      M      T     W      Th        F       S
Breakfast     S        S       M       S      S        S       S
Dinner         S        S       S      M      S        S       M
Okay! That should be it for fairly
splitting up the chores!
Yes.
Starting today, this is your home,
so you can take advantage
of everything here.
Yes.
Man. All you keep saying is yes, yes, yes.
It's so depressing!
You're a boy, aren't you?
Act like a man! Okay?
Yes.
Oh well.
Why don't you go take a bath and
scrub away all those bad memories?
Bathing is the laundry of life.
Miss Misato!
What?
A p... p... p...
Oh, him? He's one of those new
hot spring penguins.
What...
His name is Pen Pen.
He's your other roommate.
Why don't you cover that up?
Toothpicks
I wonder if I've been a little bit TOO cheery?
Maybe I'm the one who's transparent.
Miss Misato Katsuragi.
She's not a bad person.
Bathing is the laundry of life.
But bad memories always seem to find me
when I'm in the bath.
My father
and Rei Ayanami...
So, how was Rei today?
You went to the hospital this
afternoon, didn't you?
She'll be ready to work again in twenty days.
By then, we'll be ready to re-activate
Unit 00 from cryo-stasis.
It must be so hard on those children.
There is no one else who can pilot the Evas.
As long as they survive, that is what
I'll have them do.
With no regard to what they may want?
Little Shin's Room
No. 1 Public Middle School Transfer Application
Shinji Ikari
Yeah, after all the horrible stuff
he went through,
there's no telling if he'll pilot it again.
Maintaining him is part of your job.
I'm just scared. I don't know
how to deal with him.
Grumbling already? You were the one
who had the bright idea of taking him in.
Shut up!
That time, I was thinking of Shinji as a tool.
I'm as bad as Ritsuko.
We destroyed that Angel.
But I guess I can't be happy about it.
Another ceiling I don't know.
Of course. In this whole city,
there's no place that's familiar.
This is your home.
Why am I here?
The head has been damaged!
Extent of damage, unknown!
We're having problems
maintaining activation!
Status report!
The synchrograph is reversing!
The pulses are flowing backward!
Break the circuit! Block it!
We can't!
It's rejecting the signal! It won't take it!
What about Shinji?
His monitors aren't responding.
Life signs unknown!
Unit 01 's gone completely silent!
Misato!
This is it.
Abort the operation!
Rescuing the pilot is our first priority!
Force eject the entry plug!
We can't! It's completely out of control!
What the hell?!
The Eva's re-activating!
Impossible! There's no way it can move!
It can't be...
It's gone berserk?
It looks like we've won.
An AT field!
No! As long as the Angel
has that AT field up...
He can't touch the Angel!
Left arm, regenerated!
Incredible!
Unit 01 has deployed its AT field!
It's neutralizing the phase space!
No, it's eroding it!
It went through that AT field so easily...
It's going to self-destruct?!
Is the Eva...
That must be the Eva's...
true form.
Circuits reconnected.
Systems restored. Graphs back to normal.
Pilot life signs, confirmed.
Send out the recovery team. Hurry!
Preserving the pilot's life is our first priority.
Shinji, I'm coming in.
I forgot to tell you something.
You did a very praiseworthy thing today.
You should be proud of yourself.
Good night, Shinji.
Hang in there.
To Be Continued
Preview
As Shinji lives his new life,
drifting along without direction,
there was no way for him to make friends.
But the fact that he is an Eva pilot
makes him popular in his class.
Next Evangelion: "The Silent Phone"
I'll give you fan service next time too!
THE SILENT PHONE